They're all doing it for the purpose of saving lives. When my own father collapsed a few years ago from a cardiac arrest, one of the first volunteers to arrive to save my father was one of these Muslim volunteers from east Jerusalem who was in the first course to join Hatzalah. And he saved my father. Could you imagine how I felt in that moment? When I started this organization, I was 17 years old. I never imagined that one day I'd be speaking at TEDMED. I never even knew what TEDMED was then. I don't think it existed, but I never imagined, I never imagined that it's going to go all around, it's going to spread around, and this last year we started in Panama and Brazil. All I need is a partner who is a little meshugenah like me, passionate about saving lives, and willing to do it. And I'm actually starting it in India very soon with a friend who I met in Harvard just a while back. Hatzalah actually started in Brooklyn by a Hasidic Jew years before us in Williamsburg, and now it's all over the Jewish community in New York, even Australia and Mexico and many other Jewish communities. But it could spread everywhere. It's very easy to adopt. You even saw these volunteers in New York saving lives in the World Trade Center. Last year alone, we treated in Israel 207,000 people. Forty-two thousand of them were life-threatening situations. And we made a difference. I guess you could call this a lifesaving flash mob, and it works. When I look all around here, I see lots of people who would go an extra mile, run an extra mile to save other people, no matter who they are, no matter what religion, no matter who, where they come from. We all want to be heroes. We just need a good idea, motivation and lots of chutzpah, and we could save millions of people that otherwise would not be saved. Thank you very much. (Applause)
Todos lo hacen con el propósito de salvar vidas. Cuando mi propio padre se desplomó hace unos años de un ataque al corazón, uno de los primeros voluntarios en llegar a salvar a mi padre fue uno de esos voluntarios musulmanes de Jerusalén Oriental que formó parte del primer grupo que se unió a Hatzalah. Y él salvó a mi padre. ¿Se imaginan cómo me sentí en aquel momento? Cuando fundé esta organización, tenía 17 años. Nunca imaginé que un día daría una charla en TEDMED. Entonces ni siquiera sabía lo que era TEDMED. No creo que existiera, pero nunca imaginé, nunca imaginé que fuera a llegar a todas partes, se va a difundir, y el año pasado comenzamos en Panamá y Brasil. Solo necesito un socio que sea un poco meshugenah como yo, entusiasmado por salvar vidas, y deseando hacerlo. Y de hecho voy a empezar en India dentro de muy poco con un amigo que conocí en Harvard hace poco tiempo. De hecho Hatzalah se fundó en Brooklyn por un judío jasídico, años antes que nosotros en Williamsburg, y ahora está dispersa por toda la comunidad judía de Nueva York, y hasta en Australia y en México y en muchas otras comunidades judías. Pero se podría extender a todas partes. Es muy fácil de adoptar. Uds. vieron a aquellos voluntarios en Nueva York salvando vidas en el World Trade Center. Solo en el año pasado tratamos en Israel 207.000 personas. De ellas, 42.000 eran situaciones de vida o muerte. Y nosotros marcamos la diferencia. Supongo que uno podría llamarlo una multitud relámpago salvavidas, y funciona. Al mirar a mi alrededor, aquí, veo mucha gente que dedicaría el esfuerzo necesario, dedicaría la energía necesaria para salvar a otros, sin importarles quienes son, sin importarles de qué religión, sin importarles quienes son o de dónde vienen. Todos queremos ser héroes. Solo necesitamos una buena idea, motivación y un montón de audacia, y así podríamos salvar a millones de personas que de otra manera no se salvarían. Muchas gracias. (Aplausos)